Janes mss., 1865-1900 LMC 1402
Lilly Library
Janes mss.
1865-1900
Lilly Library
Janes, Lewis George.
LMC 1402
1 folio
The Janes mss., 1865-1900, consist of letters to Lewis George Janes, 1844-1901, from William Lloyd Garrison, 1805-1879; William Lloyd Garrison, Jr., 1838-1909; William James, 1842-1910; and Herbert Spencer, 1820-1903.
Access Restrictions
This collection is open for research.
Many collections are housed offsite; retrieval requires advance notice. Please make an appointment a minimum of one week in advance of your visit.
Biographical Note
Lewis George Janes, 1844-1901, was president of the Brooklyn Ethical Association from 1885-1896.
Arrangement
The letters are arranged as follows: Garrison, Jr. (1865, May 9), Garrison, Sr. (1866, Jan 23), William James (1891, Feb. 15), and Herbert Spencer (1890, 1891, 1897, and 1900).
Scope and Content Note
The Janes mss., 1865-1900, consist of letters to Lewis George Janes, 1844-1901, from William Lloyd Garrison, 1805-1879; William Lloyd Garrison, Jr., 1838-1909; William James, 1842-1910; and Herbert Spencer, 1820-1903. Many of the letters were written during the time that Janes was president of the Brooklyn Ethical Association, 1885-1896. The two Garrisons, however, writing in 1865 and 1866 respectively relate to Garrison, Sr. addressing the Union League of Rhode Island "upon our late lamented President." James writes about matters philosophical, including "the question of immortality," while Spencer's letters talk about his antagonists who continue to call him "a materialist whether you [i.e. he] like it or not," and about his poor health.
Acquisition Information
Purchase: 1998
Provenance
Barry Scott. Chicago, IL.
Lincoln, Abraham, 1809-1865 --Death and burial.; Garrison, William Lloyd, 1805-1879.; Garrison, William Lloyd, 1838-1909.; James, William, 1842-1910.; Spencer, Herbert, 1820-1903.
- Garrison, William Lloyd, 1838-1909
  - 1865, May. (Foliobox 7)
    Scope and Contents
    Writes for his father accepting the Union League of Rhode Island invitation to speak about the late President.
- Garrison, William Lloyd, 1805-1879
  - 1866, Jan. 23 (Foliobox 7)
    Thanks Janes for the additional twenty dollars voted by the Union League of Rhode Island for his lecture.
- James, William, 1842-1910
  - 1891, Feb. 15 (Foliobox 7)
    re: Positivism, Idealism immortality
- Spencer, Herbert, 1820-1903
  - 1890, May 12 (Foliobox 7)
  - 1891, May 4 (Foliobox 7)
  - 1897, June 13 (Foliobox 7)
  - 1900, August. (Foliobox 7)